

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Details

Vancouver 647-821-1942 abdi.elmi@rocketmail.com

Links

https://github.com/elmi-

https://www.linkedin.com/in/elmi-/

Skills

Javascript

Node.js

Ruby

React

jQuery

SQL

PostgresSQL

HTML & CSS

C#

ASP.NET MVC

Git

Profile

Full Stack Developer with nearly a decade's worth of experience within the software industry. Looking to continue my career within software as a Full Stack Developer. In addition to my skills and experiences as a web developer, my experience as a Senior Business Intelligence Developer provides me the experience of working with clients and managing large projects.

Employment History

Student Mentor, Lighthouse Labs, remote

MARCH 2022 - PRESENT

- mentor and help current Lighthouse Labs Web Development students find programming bugs or resolve technical issues
- helped refactor students' code to help with simplicity and efficiency

Business Intelligence Developer, Centre for Addiction and Mental Health (CAMH), Toronto

JANUARY 2019 - MARCH 2020

- Worked as Senior Business Intelligence Developer building BI solutions for teams/departments throughout the hospital
- Effectively coded software end-to-end solutions for departments using Dundas BI, including and not limited to developing the current platform used by the Schizophrenia department
- Led the team in implementing the COVID-19 National Survey Dashboard
- Began the overseeing of transitioning the platform from Dundas BI to Tableau

Technical Summary: Dundas BI, SQL Server, C#, JavaScript, Microsoft Excel, Tableau

Senior Business Intelligence Consultant, Dundas Data Visualization Inc.,

APRIL 2016 - JANUARY 2019

- Work with business analysts and solution architects to gather requirements and provide effort/cost estimates for BI/Dashboard solution development work.
- Make recommendations and strategies for BI solutions based on customer requirements.
- Design, develop, test, implement and support BI solutions using Dundas BI and other software platforms to satisfy business requirements. In addition to creating BI/Dashboard solutions, I was in charge of also providing training using Dundas BI.

Technical Summary: Dundas BI, SQL Server, SSRS (OLAP), IBM DB2, C#, CSS3, HTML5, JQuery, JavaScript, Microsoft Excel Major

Clients: IBM, CAMH, Pepperidge Farm, DeMoines University

Junior Business Analyst, Support Associate, Dundas Data Visualization Inc., Toronto

JULY 2015 - APRIL 2016

- Help end users answer their questions/problems regarding the use of Dundas RI
- Provide development support using Dundas BI for Fortune 500 companies and support clients on Microsoft technologies including ASP.NET, IIS, SharePoint and SQL Server Analysis Services.

Technical Summary: Dundas BI, SQL Server, SSRS (OLAP), C#, CSS3, HTML5, JQuery, JavaScript, Microsoft Excel

Junior Web Developer, Brushfire North Inc., Toronto

APRIL 2014 - APRIL 2015

- Junior developer with Brushfire North Inc (www.brushfirenorth.com), working with ASP.NET (both MVC and Web Forms).
- Worked both as a back-end developer and front-end developer for the company, focusing 60% of my time as a front-end developer.
- The company worked closely with Agility CMS for some of their clients. In addition to being a developer, I did some design work, producing PSD mockups for desktop and mobile projects.

Technical Summary: ASP.NET MVC 4, C#, CSS3, HTML5, JQuery, JavaScript, TFS, SVN, Adobe PhotoShop CC 2014, JIRA

Education

Web Development Bootcamp, Lighthouse Labs, Vancouver

OCTOBER 2021 - JANUARY 2022

Computer Programming and Analysis, George Brown College, Toronto

JANUARY 2012 - APRIL 2014

Projects

The Office Quiz

MARCH 2022

Full-stack project built on a React front-end and Node back-end using <u>officeapi.dev</u> API

Link: https://github.com/elmi-/office-quiz

FantasyRadar

JANUARY 2022 - JANUARY 2022

Web app that scraps Basketball-Reference and fetches latest news for users and notifies users via text messages using Twilio API, all built with Ruby on Rails

Link: https://github.com/elmi-/FantasyRadar

scheduler

DECEMBER 2021 - DECEMBER 2021

Single page application built using React! Data is presisted by an API server using a PostgreSQL database.

Link: https://github.com/elmi-/scheduler

TinyApp

NOVEMBER 2021 - DECEMBER 2021

TinyApp is a full stack web application built with Node and Express that allows users to shorten long URLs (à la bit.ly).

Link: https://github.com/elmi-/tinyapp